ERIC RANKIN

9532 N Kalmar St • Portland, OR 97203 918-894-0625 • Ejrankin@Gmail.com

ENGINEERING TECHNICIAN

Quality-focused, project-conscious engineer talented in evaluating TV Production processes and establishing automation strategies to support daily broadcast requirements. Skilled problem-solver and communicator utilizing excellent analytical, troubleshooting, and engineering expertise to evaluate systems and make emergency repairs as needed. Adept in identifying project requirements and developing effective solutions to continually improve operations.

Technical Proficiency...

Platforms:Windows, Mac OS X

Applications: Microsoft Office, Filemaker Pro, iLog, Discrepsoft, Protrack, AutoSat, CompuSat, Crispin Automation, Harris Automation, Pro Bel Morpheus Automation, Dekocast, Viz Client, Avid iNews Command

Hardware: Network Routers, Master Control Switcher, Intercom Systems, EAS Encoder/Decoder

EDUCATION

Associates Degree in Liberal Arts & Science Moorpark College, Moorpark, CA

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

OREGON PUBLIC BROADCASTING, PORTLAND, OR

3/2013 TO CURRENT

Master Control Operator(on-call)

Recruited to oversee and monitor all broadcast signal feeds for Oregon Public Broadcasting, including OPB HD and OPB Plus. Position involves utilizing and maintaining Crispin Automation to ensure quality broadcasting. Ingesting, preparation and playback of broadcast materials from broadcast servers. Responsible for setting up satellite feeds for automated records and VTR backup.

XEROX BUSINESS SERVICES, TIGARD, OR

12/2013 TO 7/2013

Technical Support Advisor

Technical support for the Apple project. Responsible for troubleshooting system-wide and user-specific issues with Apple CPU. Position involves technical expertise with Mac OS X platform and providing excellent customer service.

GRIFFIN COMMUNICATIONS, TULSA, OK

7/2010 to 8/2012

Engineering Technician

Recruited to oversee and monitor all broadcast signal feeds for KOTV and KQCW, Tulsa CBS / CW affiliate members. Supervised and coordinated operations for all playback equipment, configuring, and monitoring computer based automation systems. Provided technical

...continued

ERIC RANKIN

PAGE TWO

expertise in troubleshooting on air network and studio feeds, accurately maintaining all on air logs and discrepancy reports. Coordinate communication between supervisors and other department heads regarding satellite configurations, encoding video for server playback, and monitoring station transmitters.

TV Guide Network, Tulsa, OK

03/2008 to 07/2010

Master Control Operator

Coordinated operations for all playback equipment, configuring, and monitoring computer based automation systems. Directed all aspects of configuring and tuning CompuSat and digital / analog satellite feeds to obtain on air material. Evaluated and troubleshot technical issues, ensuring highest quality commercial video / audio productions. Operated waveform monitors, vector and audio scopes, recording machines, and server operations.